[
    {
        "question": "Which is considered as the biggest port of India ?",
        "option1": "kolkata",
        "option2": "Cochin",
        "option3": "Chennai",
        "option4": "Mumbai",
        "answer": "Mumbai"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gas used for making vegetables is ?",
        "option1": "Oxygen",
        "option2": "Carbon dioxide",
        "option3": "Hydrogen",
        "option4": "Nitrogen",
        "answer": "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hottest planet in the solar system ?",
        "option1": "Mercury",
        "option2": "Venus",
        "option3": "Jupiter",
        "option4": "Saturn",
        "answer": "Venus"
    },
    {
        "question": "One People, One State, One leader” was the policy of ?",
        "option1": "Stalin",
        "option2": "Hitler",
        "option3": "Lenin",
        "option4": "Mussolin",
        "answer": "Hitler"
    },
    {
        "question": "The river that flows through Delhi is ?",
        "option1": "Ganga",
        "option2": "Indus",
        "option3": "Yamuna",
        "option4": "Narmada",
        "answer": "Yamuna"
    },
    {
        "question": "National Income estimates in India are prepared by",
        "option1": "Planning Commission",
        "option2": "Reserve Bank of India",
        "option3": "Central statistical organisation",
        "option4": "Indian statistical Institute",
        "answer": "Central statistical organisation"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tropic of cancer does not pass through which of these Indian states ?",
        "option1": "Madhya Pradesh",
        "option2": "West Bengal",
        "option3": "Rajasthan",
        "option4": "Odisha",
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fathometer is used to measure",
        "option1": "Earthquakes",
        "option2": "Rainfall",
        "option3": "Ocean depth",
        "option4": "Sound intensity",
        "answer": "Ocean depth"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purest form of iron is",
        "option1": "wrought iron",
        "option2": "steel",
        "option3": "pig iron",
        "option4": "nickel steel",
        "answer": "wrought iron"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many colours are there in a rainbow?",
        "option1": "9",
        "option2": "7",
        "option3": "6",
        "option4": "8",
        "answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which animal is known as the ‘Ship of the Desert?",
        "option1": "Lion",
        "option2": "Tiger",
        "option3": "Camel",
        "option4": "Rat",
        "answer": "Camel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which month of the year has the least number of days?",
        "option1": "January",
        "option2": "Februrary",
        "option3": "April",
        "option4": "May",
        "answer": "Februrary"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gir National Park in Gujarat is famous for?",
        "option1": "Elephant",
        "option2": "Rhinoceros",
        "option3": "Lion",
        "option4": "Tiger",
        "answer": "Lion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Smallest state of India is?",
        "option1": "Goa",
        "option2": "Assam",
        "option3": "Jammu & Kashmir",
        "option4": "Sikkim",
        "answer": "Goa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following month have 31 days?",
        "option1": "October",
        "option2": "February",
        "option3": "June",
        "option4": "April",
        "answer": "October"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an outdoor game?",
        "option1": "Cricket",
        "option2": "Football",
        "option3": "Hockey",
        "option4": "Table tennis",
        "answer": "Table tennis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Young one of a cat is called?",
        "option1": "Calf",
        "option2": "Kitten",
        "option3": "Puppy",
        "option4": "Cub",
        "answer": "Kitten"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prime Minister of India is?",
        "option1": "Manmohan Singh",
        "option2": "Narendra Modi",
        "option3": "Sonia Gandhi",
        "option4": "Pranab Mukherjee",
        "answer": "Narendra Modi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who invented Computer?",
        "option1": "Thomas Alva Edison",
        "option2": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "option3": "Charles Babbage",
        "option4": "Pascal",
        "answer": "Charles Babbage"
    },
    {
        "question": "Capital of United States of America (USA) is:",
        "option1": "New York",
        "option2": "San Fransisco",
        "option3": "California",
        "option4": "Washington D.C",
        "answer": "Washington D.C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Brightest planet of the solar system is?",
        "option1": "Mercury",
        "option2": "Venus",
        "option3": "Jupiter",
        "option4": "Saturn",
        "answer": "Venus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who among the following sports personalities has been awarded Padma Vibhushan for the year 2020?",
        "option1": "Virat Kohli",
        "option2": "P V Sindhu",
        "option3": "Rohit Sharma",
        "option4": "M. C. Mary Kom",
        "answer": "M. C. Mary Kom"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Educational technology, application of psychology is known as -",
        "option1": "Software approach",
        "option2": "Hardware approach",
        "option3": "Pedagogic approach",
        "option4": "Systems analysis",
        "answer": "Software approach"
    },
    {
        "question": "The World Largest desert is ",
        "option1": "TharB",
        "option2": "Sahara",
        "option3": "Kalahari",
        "option4": "Sonoran",
        "answer": "Sahara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which soil is suitable for agriculture ?",
        "option1": "Red soil",
        "option2": "Black soil",
        "option3": "Peaty soil",
        "option4": "Sand",
        "answer": "Peaty soil"
    },
    {
        "question": "The device used for measuring altitudes is ?",
        "option1": "altimeter",
        "option2": "ammeter",
        "option3": "audiometer",
        "option4": "galvanometer",
        "answer": "altimeter"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Gate way of India is ?",
        "option1": "Chennai",
        "option2": "Mumbai",
        "option3": "Agra",
        "option4": "Delhi",
        "answer": "Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission was ?",
        "option1": "Dr.C.V.Raman",
        "option2": "Dr.H.J.Bhabha",
        "option3": "Dr.A.P.J.Abdul Kalam",
        "option4": "Dr.Vickram Sarabhai",
        "answer": "Dr.H.J.Bhabha"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many hours are there in two days?",
        "option1": "46",
        "option2": "54",
        "option3": "44",
        "option4": "48",
        "answer": "48"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many millimetres are there in 1cm?",
        "option1": "100",
        "option2": "1000",
        "option3": "10",
        "option4": "10000",
        "answer": "10"
    }


]